https://orangefield.org.uk/privacy-notice/

DATA PRIVACY NOTICE
The Kirk Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church, Belfast
1. Your personal data – what is it?Personal data relates to a living individual (the “data subject”) who can be identified from that data.  Identification can be by the information alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controller’s possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”).
2. Who are we?The Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church (contact details below) is the data controller.  This means it decides how your personal data is processed and for what purposes.
3. How do we process your personal data?The Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church complies with its obligations under the “GDPR” by keeping personal data up to date; by storing and destroying it securely; by not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data; by protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure and by ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
We use your personal data for the following purposes:• To enable us to watch over and promote the spiritual interest of the congregation;• To help us to provide pastoral care to the congregation;• To further the contribution of the church to Christian witness and service in the local community;• To administer membership records;• To fundraise and promote the interests of the charity;• To manage our employees and volunteers;• To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications);• To contact individuals via surveys to conduct research about their opinions;• To inform you of news, prayer requests, events, activities and services running at Orangefield.
4. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?• Explicit consent of the data subject so that we can keep you informed about news, events, activities and services and process your gift aid donations and keep you informed about church events;• Processing is necessary for carrying out obligations under employment, social security or social protection law, or a collective agreement;• Processing is carried out by a not-for-profit body with a political, philosophical, religious or trade union aim provided:- the processing relates only to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes); and- there is no disclosure to a third party without consent.
5. Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as strictly confidential and will only be shared with other members of the church in order to carry out a service to other church members or for purposes connected with the church. We won’t share your data with third parties outside of the church without your consent.
7. Your rights and your personal dataUnless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:
• The right to request a copy of your personal data which the Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church holds about you;• The right to request that the Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;• The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church to retain such data;• The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time;• The right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and, where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable) [Only applies where the processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of a contract with the data subject and in either case the data controller processes the data by automated means].• The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;• The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable) [Only applies where processing is based on legitimate interests (or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing and processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics]• The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).
7. Your rights and your personal dataUnless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:
• The right to request a copy of your personal data which the Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church holds about you;• The right to request that the Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church corrects any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;• The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for the Session of Orangefield Presbyterian Church to retain such data;• The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time;• The right to request that the data controller provide the data subject with his/her personal data and, where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller, (known as the right to data portability), (where applicable) [Only applies where the processing is based on consent or is necessary for the performance of a contract with the data subject and in either case the data controller processes the data by automated means].• The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;• The right to object to the processing of personal data, (where applicable) [Only applies where processing is based on legitimate interests (or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority); direct marketing and processing for the purposes of scientific/historical research and statistics]• The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).
8. Further processingIf we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Data Protection Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
9. Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights, queries of complaints please in the first instance contact the Church Office at:
Orangefield Presbyterian Church
464 Castlereagh Road
BELFAST
BT5 6BH
Phone: 028 9079 9391
Email:
You can contact the Information Commissioner’s Office at:
The Information Commissioner’s Office
Wycliffe House
Water Lane
Wilmslow
Cheshire
SK9 5AF
Phone 0303 123 1113
Email https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email
10. What do you need to do now?We would very much like to continue contacting you in a variety of ways, including email and telephone.  If you are willing to continue receiving such communications, please complete a Consent Form (available from the Church Office or in the Resource Area) and return it to the office.Also, if you have recently changed – or intend to change – your home address, phone number, email address or any other personal details, please let us know through the Church Office so that we can update our records.
Sign Up To Our Weekly Updates
First Name*Last Name*Email Address*
Get Involved / Serve
Give
Find Us
Privacy Notice
© ORANGEFIELD PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.
CHARITY NO. NIC104513
TEL: 02890 799391  •  464 Castlereagh Road, Belfast, BT5 6BH  •
